Elliott McDonald

Elliottmcd1998@hotmail.co.uk • 07896217796

LinkedIn • https://www.linkedin.com/in/elliott-mcdonald-3636ba186/

Kiln Cottage, Mill Lane, Caunton, Newark, Nottingham, NG236AJ

Personal Statement

An enthusiastic, self-motivated final year student at the University of Lincoln studying Computer Science (BSc) with strong experience in C#, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and the development of applications for desktop, mobile devices and web. Self-taught Python and Unity for the purposes of producing a final year thesis and completed a three month internship at Experian as a data management intern producing an Alteryx tool using Python. This would be an excellent opportunity to apply and improve on skills acquired throughout University in a positive working environment.

Education

University of Lincoln • September 2017 - Present

BSC Computer Science

Predicted to attain a first-class honours degree having achieved a first throughout second year and the first semester of third year.

Key Modules

Cross-Platform Development (Marks not yet received)

This module required the design and creation of a cross-platform mobile application created with respect to the five planes of user experience and coding in react-native. Along with product design techniques, this taught the use of JavaScript and the use of DOM elements that can be applied to React.js where required.

Object-Oriented Programming (Attained 73%)

Having learnt basic C# programming in first year, further Object-Oriented techniques were presented in second year through C++. This module taught more advanced programming features such as pointers, operator overloading and virtual functions. The assessment required a nearest neighbour search to be coded in an object-oriented style to find a given image within a larger scene image.

Database Systems (Attained 69%)

In this module students were first required to design a relational database for the management of stock, orders and staff within a computer repairs company. Students worked in groups to determine primary and foreign keys, create an entity relationship diagram and normalise their database model up to the third normal form. There was also the requirement to individually write MySQL code to create a database using all basic functions as well as creating stored procedures.

Minster School and Sixth Form • 2010 - 2017

A-levels: Computer Science, Maths, Biology (B, C, C).

GCSE: Maths, English, Science (A, B, A), 7 additional GCSE's grade B or above.

Work Experience

. Experian – Data Management Intern ● May 2019 – September 2019

Worked as part of an agile data management and software development team within Experian. Main responsibility was creating a program using Python to track specific data through workflows within Alteryx modules to allow other developers to better understand the flows of certain modules. The team worked in two-week sprints with scrum meetings every morning. This internship also included mentoring another intern for a week.

The Caunton Beck – Kitchen Porter

November 2016 – May 2019

Worked as a kitchen porter at The Caunton Beck out of semester time. Responsibilities included washing all the kitchenware and ensuring everything was cleaned to a professional standard along

with preparing food to be cooked and served. Involved working in a fast-paced environment and collaborating with colleagues to ensure everything ran smoothly.

Jaycee's PC's - Shop Assistant • 2015

Worked as a shop assistant for Jaycee's PC's based in Worksop for a week. This included fixing any software or hardware problems customers had with their devices. Provided excellent customer service through providing solutions and explaining potential fixes to them.

Technical Skills

· Coding

Proficient in multiple programming languages and can adapt to any programming standards as required. Enjoys generating innovative solutions to complex technical problems by carefully analysing business requirements and understanding workflow and end user needs. Has a passion for producing creative new programs and actively learning emerging programming languages and techniques.

Problem Solving

Enjoys solving complex problems related to coding through logical and resourceful thinking, as shown by the final version of https://elliottmcd98.github.io/. In the creation of this, many problems were encountered such as image resizing for different devices; however, all these issues were solved through research and perseverance which are applied in all endeavours.

Soft Skills

Motivated

Keen to make sure jobs are perfected and enjoys doing work outside of course materials in spare time. This is shown through having acquired multiple MTA certificates including HTML5 Application Development Fundamentals - Certified 2018, Database Fundamentals - Certified 2019 and Introduction to Programming Using Python - Certified 2019. As well as this, Unity games created in free time from learning game development through an online Udemy course.

Communication

Excellent interpersonal skills developed and utilised through working at the Caunton Beck, by coordinating with other staff to ensure the kitchen functioned efficiently. This was also useful when given a leadership role at Experian through having to train another intern on how to use the company software and teaching new programming techniques. Is highly capable of working well within a team and is proficient when using techniques such as paired programming.

· Time Management

Experian required good time management through having to ensure the project being working on was completed before departure as well as through working in an agile environment with the rest of the team. Developed exceptional organisational skills attaining good grades in academic studies simultaneously with extra-curricular activities, such as passing Grade 8 piano and studying Udemy courses. Able to adapt whenever required to accommodate time critical assignments.

Interests

Games Programming

Revels in coding games in spare time through studying from YouTube materials as well as online Udemy courses such as "Complete C# Unity Developer 2D" and through this, learning new coding techniques.

Music

Has played the piano (Grade 8) and guitar for over eight years. These skills were improved through completing AS Level Music at Sixth Form. Likes learning new interesting and challenging pieces on piano and playing for family and friends.

References available on request.